A Guide to the American War Mothers, Richmond Chapter, records, 1931-1957
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
American War Mothers, Richmond Chapter, records, 1931-1957
The Library of Virginia
30149
1 cu. ft. and 2 boxes
American War Mothers, Richmond Chapter
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. W. Milton Engard, Sr., 1308 Bainbridge Street, Richmond, Virginia, per Lynn E. Wright, 5409 Glyndon Lane, Richmond, Virginia.
Historical Information
The American War Mothers was organized in 1917 and incorporated by Act of Congress on 4 February 1925 for Mothers of sons and daughters who served during World War I or II, the Korean War, or any subsequent war involving the U.S., and were honorably discharged. The Richmond Chapter was charted 6 May 1931.
Scope and Content
Records, 1931-1957, of the American War Mothers, Richmond Chapter, consisting of membership applications, 1931-1957, to the society which contain the name, address, date and place of marriage of the mother and her husband, and information about her son or daughter in the service, such as the name, place of birth, address, name of spouse, date and place of marriage, branch and company, and date and cause of death. Also includes minutes, 1944-1953, of monthly meetings, an inventory of property, 1956-1957, correspondence, 1953-1955, and miscellaneous applications, cards, conference programs, receipts, reports, regulations or rituals, all 1943-1956, a charter for the chapter, 6 May 1931, and flags, one being a flag of the chapter.
Collection contains one application from Raleigh, North Carolina, dated 28 September 1928.
Contents List
- Applications for membership, 1931-1939, includes one application dated 28 September 1928 from Raleigh, North Carolina. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Applications for membership, 1942-1948. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Applications for membership, 1950-1957. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes of monthly meetings, 1944. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes of monthly meetings, 1945-1946. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes of monthly meetings, 1948-1953. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes of monthly meetings, 1951-1952. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1953-1955. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Inventory of property, 1956-1957. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Micellaneous applications, cards, programs, receipts, reports, newsletters, and rituals, 1943-1956. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Charter of Richmond chapter, 6 May 1931. (Box 2 (oversize), Folder 1)
- Flags. (Box 2 (oversize), Folder 2)